Riley Flarity

Greater Seattle Area



rileyflarity@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/riley-flarity

Summary

I am a versatile engineer with experience in systems design, scripting and automating tasks using python, java and Linux. Friendly and outgoing with a willingness to help in any way. Learning is a continuous process and I always take advantage given the opportunity.

Experience



Associate Engineer, Service Operations

Betacom

Aug 2022 - Present (6 months)

Member of Services and Operations team.

- Responsible for front ending customer issues, proactive monitoring, and execution of proactive and preventive maintenance activities.
- Ensure that requests are properly logged, assigned, and responded to in a timely manner and according to agreed SLA's.
- Perform maintenance and push out patches as per client schedule.
- Troubleshoot, install and repair 5G Networks on premise and cloud setup.
- Monitor health and system alerts, and act according to SLA.
- Manage customer portal and trouble tickets using Jira and SNOW.
- Explore automation opportunities for repeat actions and work along with AI Ops team.

🟗 Application Support Engineer

Internetwork Engineering

Aug 2021 - Mar 2022 (8 months)

Member of Software Development team.

- Consume, build and store various network elements relating to services in production on a Restful API using Node.js and Nest.js framework.
- Perform data ingestion using Python and TypeScript from Infoblox and other network data sources.
- Attend daily standup and bi-weekly scrum meetings where tasks are assigned from a Jira storyboard.

T Engineer

T-Mobile

Oct 2020 - Aug 2021 (11 months)

Member of Advanced Technical Support (ATS) Engineer for T-Mobile Messaging Databases.

Primary engineer running the expansion of the OTA platform, including tasks:

- Python scripting to create, read, update and delete from the Oracle SQL database.
- Request and verify new virtual machines from pod datacenter. Update existing host files with legacy platform and permission access to appropriate users.
- Validate application version is compatible with new VM instances and that all production relevant software is installed prior to bring from development into production.

- Collaborate with application team to schedule MW with stakeholders and attempt to hold multiple events in a single night to minimize overall impact to production.
- Setup AppDynamics, FireEye, Splunk, Puppet and validate the discovery on Service Now.
- Create new firewall rules on Atlassian Jira and validate traffic flows through all new and old sources.
- Automate tasks primarily done on the command line and set up email alerts.
- Lead troubleshooting calls to minimize outages and impact to core business and customers.

Associate Engineer

T-Mobile

Sep 2018 - Oct 2020 (2 years 2 months)

Member of Tier 2 Converged Messaging Sustainment Team.

Support T-Mobile's production network and solutions design review, validation, testing and operations acceptance for all new or expansion nodes/platforms or services being introduced into T-Mobile Voice, Data, Messaging and Mobile Internet wireless networks.

Key member in developing new tools for network and customer support teams including:

- Build a guick reference guides and information lookup for relevant troubleshooting of messaging platforms.
- Modernize scripts using bash and curl to accessible and invoked on a front-end Apache interface.
- Take requests to create displays of KPI metrics and email alerts depending on the priority need .
- Solve tickets and troubleshoot individual issues to determine if it is user related or network.
- Hold conference calls explaining operation and use case of any tools created with customer facing teams.
- Work rotating on-call shifts and deploy new software patching during MW activities.

Technology Intern

T-Mobile

Jun 2018 - Sep 2018 (4 months)

Utilize software skills using JavaScript, Python, PHP, PERL and more to create the 'TRCED' T-Mobile Real-Time Customer Experience Dashboard.

Create and manage database generated from back end Splunk gueries based on CDR/TRL data logs from RHEL production servers taking real customer traffic.

Use google charts to graph 15 minute intervals of data based on metrics from SIP, Diameter and HTTP response codes.

Education



W University of Washington Tacoma

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Computer Science & Systems Sep 2017 - Jun 2019

Green River College

Associate of Science - AS, Computer Science Sep 2016 - Jun 2017